Isshiki-senpai, we're back!
（幸平創真(ゆきひらそうま)）
一色先輩！　帰って来たっす
Welcome back, everyone!
（一色慧(いっしきさとし)）みんな おかえり！
あの地獄の合宿を生き抜いたんだね
I see that all of you survived the camp from hell.
Good job-
本当に おつかれさま…
We are back.
ただいまぁ
Souma-kun?!
（一色）創真君？
一段とたくましくなって…
You look so much more manly.
The tasks must've been very challenging!
よほど課題が厳しかったと見える
Chew, chew, chew.
（田所恵(たどころめぐみ)）クチャクチャ…
Tadokoro-chan?!
（一色）田所ちゃん？
田所ちゃんなのかい？
Is that really you, Tadokoro-chan?
You're all kinds of rough around the edges!
みんなも なんだかヤサぐれて
Shut your trap!
（恵）うっせえです！
（一色）はっ？
Huh?!
（吉野悠姫(よしのゆうき)）
ウッシッシッシッシ　姉御
こいつ袋にしちまいましょうぜ
Boss!
Whaddya say we beat the crap out of him?
Let's do it!
（青木(あおき)大吾(だいご)･佐藤昭二(さとうしょうじ)）
しちまいやしょうぜ
Hey! All of you better respect your elders,
（榊涼子(さかきりょうこ)）パイセンに
失礼ブッこいてんじゃねえよ
or there's gonna be hell to pay!
あたいが許さんぜ
Ibusaki-kun, your charming hairstyle's been ruined.
（一色）伊武崎君 いつもの
チャーミングなヘアスタイルが―
台無しじゃないか
Scruff.
（伊武崎峻(いぶさきしゅん)）モジャ…
（一色）ああ…
あっ そう言えば丸井君は？
彼だけ姿が見えないようだが
Come to think of it, where's Marui-kun?
I don't see him with you.
This was all that we could find of him.
（伊武崎）
回収できたのは これだけだ
Th-This can't be...
そっ… そんな！
（一色）うっ… 丸井君！
Marui-kun!
It was only a dream.
夢か
Today is the third day of camp.
今日で合宿は３日目
（鶏の鳴き声）
みんな どうか無事で
I hope you're all okay.
ひいっ…
No good!
（講師）なっとらん　作り直し！
（女子生徒Ａ）ひいっ
Start over!
Good, you pass the test.
（講師）うん 合格だ
片付けていいぞ　田所恵
You may clean up now, Tadokoro Megumi.
あっ ありがとうございます
Thank you!
（恵）エヘッ
（恵）あっ あ…
（男子生徒Ａ）どけよ　邪魔だ！
Watch where you're going!
S-Sorry!
ごっ ごめんなさい～
Nice work, Tadokoro.
（創真）やるじゃん 田所
まだ危なっかしいところもあるけど
You've still got some rough patches, but...
Not enough.
足りねえ　まだ ちっとも…
Still not enough.
Perfect!
上等！
I have to do better.
もっと腕を上げねえと
I have to!
もっと！
Eggs Before Dawn
（薙切(なきり)えりな）んっ
You'd best relieve yourself of the notion that you can stay the queen bee forever.
（薙切(なきり)アリス）
いつまでも女王様気取りで…
いられると思わないでね
Thank you for the advice.
忠告ありがとう
I'll do my best to keep what you said in mind...
一応 頭に入れておきます
as the prattle of the unwashed masses.
下々の戯言(ざれごと)としてね
（悠姫）うわぁ～
Today was another tough one!
今日もキツかったぁ～
あぅ… 早く部屋で寝たい
I want to pass out in my room already.
We only have two more days of this.
でも 残りはあと２日
We might scrape by.
（涼子）ギリギリ何とかなるかもね
（丸井）う… うっ…
Strange.
あら 今夜の就寝時間が書いてない
I don't see a time listed for lights out.
んっ？　ほんとだな
You're right.
Maybe it got left out by mistake?
（悠姫）印刷ミスじゃない？
Students of Tohtsuki Academy!
（堂島銀(どうじまぎん)）遠月(とおつき)学園 全生徒の諸君
One hour from now, at ten o'clock,
今から１時間後 22時に―
assemble in the banquet hall in your uniforms.
制服に着替えて
大宴会場に集合してくれ
What?!
What the hell?
（青木）何だ？
（佐藤）めんどくせぇ
What a drag.
Wow, the herd's really thinned out.
（創真）
なんか だいぶ数減ったなぁ
Everyone's exhausted, of course.
（涼子）
やっぱり みんなボロボロね
What could they have planned
at this time of night?
こんな時間に一体 何が…
Yukihira!
（タクミ･アルディーニ）幸平！
（創真）あ…
Hey!
（水戸(みと)郁魅(いくみ)）てめえな！
卒業生と食戟(しょくげき)なんて―
Don't go pulling ridiculous stunts like challenging an alumnus to a Cooking Battle, idiot!
むちゃしてんなよ バカ野郎！
How dare you risk getting kicked out of Tohtsuki without first settling your score with me?!
俺との決着をつけず
学園を去るなんて 許さないぞ！
Who the hell are you?
（郁魅）何だよ てめえは
（タクミ）君こそ何だ
That's my line.
How did you guys know
about the Cooking Battle?
２人はなんで
俺らの食戟のこと知ってんの？
Everyone's been talking about it!
（郁魅･タクミ）そこら中で
うわさになってんだよ！
Hang on. If Yukihira's here right now,
wouldn't that mean...
でも幸平がここにいるってことは…
No way! You beat Chef Shinomiya?!
まさか四宮(しのみや)シェフに…
Did you really?!
（タクミ･郁魅）そうなのか？
あ… いや
Nah, I blew it.
すげえ負けた
Huh?!
ええっ　そうなの… か
Is that so?
Can we please stop talking about this?
いやぁ　だから もう聞かんでくれ
No way! Explain yourself!
説明しやがれ！
何がどうなったのか
What happened?!
Hey!
（男子生徒Ｂ）おっ 見ろよ
（女子生徒Ｂ）ああ…
Look!
（男子生徒Ｃ）えりな様
（男子生徒Ｄ）えりな様だ
Erina-sama!
It's Erina-sama.
All eyes up front!
（堂島）全員 ステージに注目
We've gathered all of you here for one reason and one reason only:
集まってもらったのは他でもない
to explain to you what tomorrow's task will be.
明日の課題について連絡するためだ
明日の？
Tomorrow?
Why bother telling us that the night before?
なんで それを前日の夜に？
Your assignment will be to create a new breakfast menu worthy of being served to the guests of Tohtsuki Resort.
（堂島）課題内容は―
この遠月リゾートのお客様に
提供するにふさわしい―
朝食の新メニュー作りだ
Breakfasts are the face of the hotel.
朝食はホテルの顔
宿泊客の１日の始まりを演出する
大切な食事だ
It is an important meal because it is what starts the guests' day.
I'd like you all to come up with an innovative dish that will make a vibrant contribution to the breakfast table.
そのテーブルを
晴れやかに彩るような―
Innovation
新鮮な 驚きのある一品を
提案してもらいたい
Innovation
The main ingredient will be eggs.
メインの食材は卵
Your dish may be of whatever cuisine you'd like,
和･洋･中といったジャンルは
問わないが―
but it must be capable of being served buffet style.
ビュッフェ形式での提供を
基本とする
The judging will begin at 6 o'clock tomorrow morning.
審査開始は 明日の午前６時だ
Make sure that your dish is ready by then.
その時刻に試食できるよう
準備してくれ
Did I hear that right?
私の聞き間違いかなぁ？
午後６時… だよねぇ
He meant six in the evening, right?
No, he definitely said "morning."
いいや
完全に“午前”って言ったぜ
W-Wait!
ううっ ってことは～
We have no time to waste on sleep!
寝てる場合じゃなぁ～い！
You're free to decide how to spend your time.
（堂島）
朝までの時間の使い方は自由
You can work on your recipe
in one of the many kitchens,
各厨房で支度を行うもよし
部屋で睡眠を取るもよしだ
or go and get some rest in your room.
I'll see you all again in the morning.
では 明朝また会おう
Dismissed!
解散！
（生徒たち）うわぁっ…
（男子生徒Ｅ）無理だ
No way.
もう全身がガタガタなのに
I'm already in pieces.
My brain's barely working as it is!
（男子生徒Ｆ）こんな状態で
まともに頭 働かねえよ
Finally, a task worth competing over.
ようやく
張り合いのある課題が出たな
Just you wait, Yukihira.
（タクミ）楽しみにしていろ 幸平
（創真）ん？
Hm?
I'll deliver the ultimate breakfast:
イタリアの定番卵料理を
a traditional Italian egg dish that's been prepared with the Aldinis' expertise!
アルディーニの技でアレンジした
至高の朝食を お見舞いしてやる
What's in this traditional Italian egg dish of yours?
へえ～　イタリアの定番卵料理って
どんな感じなんだ？
フン
Well, aside from the eggs, you take
some cheese and vegetables and—
（イサミ･アルディーニ）
えっとねぇ 卵に
チーズとか野菜をからめて…
どうしてバラすんだ イサミ！
What are you doing, Isami?!
Stop giving away our secrets!
それ以上のネタばらしは よせ！
C'mon, let's get out of here!
ほら もうさっさと行くぞ
Fine, fine.
（イサミ）はいはーい
Come to think of it,
my transfer exam also featured eggs.
そういや 俺の編入試験
あん時も卵がお題だったよなぁ
The main ingredient will be eggs.
（えりな）メインの食材は卵
Make one dish.
一品 作りなさい
Here you go!
おあがりよ
Doesn't this bring back memories, Nakiri?
なついなぁ　なあ 薙切
D-Don't you dare act so familiar with me!
きっ 気安く話しかけないで
A word of advice.
忠告しておくけれど―
Don't make a low-class dish like last time.
あの時のような下品な料理は
出さないことだわ
If you want to avoid embarrassing yourself in front of the judges, that is.
審査員の失笑を買いたくなければね
But it seemed like you enjoyed it, didn't you—
でも お前
うまそうに食ってたじゃねえか
はぁ？　誰が！
言ったでしょ　まずいって
Huh? What are you talking about?!
I told you that it was disgusting!
Erina-sama!
（新戸(あらと)緋沙子(ひさこ)）えりな様～
I've secured a kitchen.
調理室の手配が済みました
Very well.
（えりな）
よろしい　では向かいましょう
Let us be on our way, then.
Well, good luck racking your
nonexistent brains over this one.
まっ せいぜい
ない知恵を絞りなさい
ごきげんよう
Good day.
（悠姫）あへ… へへ… へ…
（創真）ん？
Um, are you guys all right?
（恵）あの… ２人とも大丈夫？
Fine, I'll show them what I've got!
こうなったら
根性見せてやんよーっ！
Hey, Marui! Stand up!
ほら 丸井 立ちな
絶対 みんなそろって寮に帰るよ！
We're all going back to the dorm together!
Polar Star!
Polar Star
極星(きょくせい) ファイト！　オーッ！
Fight!
Yeah!
Y-Yeah!
What a quiet night.
（堂島）静かな夜だ
It's very different from the typical scene during a task,
いつもの怒号飛び交う課題風景とは
大違いですな
what with all the yelling.
Indeed.
（ローラン･シャペル）うむ
だが 恐らく学生たちは 今―
But all things considered,
I would expect the students to be more frustrated than they'd usually be.
怒号よりも もっと激しい…
焦燥の真っ只中にいるのだ
I wonder if this'll work.
（女子生徒Ｃ）これで大丈夫かなぁ
Maybe I'll try another seasoning.
（男子生徒Ｈ）別の味付けも試すか
This assignment is more cruel than I thought.
思った以上に エグい課題だな
You're right.
そうね
Unless you're extremely confident in what you've
come up with, there's no way you'd go to bed early.
自分の料理に よほど自信がなきゃ
早々と寝る気にもなれないわね
I'm retiring to bed.
私はもう休みますが
あなたは まだ試作を？
Will you continue to test recipes?
あっ はい　まだ半ばですので
Y-Yes.
I'm still only halfway done.
I see.
（えりな）
そう　程々で切り上げなさいな
Don't stay up too late.
Erina-sama is impressive.
（緋沙子）さすが えりな様
プレッシャーなど無きが如し
Pressure doesn't exist in her world!
Her royal bearing...
超然とした態度 感服いたします
How worthy of admiration!
Oh, one more thing.
（えりな）ああ それと…
（緋沙子）あ…
Tomorrow night, we'll play Sevens!
明日の晩は ７並べで勝負よ
In the game of Old Maid yesterday...
昨日のババヌキは その…
少し不調だっただけだから
I wasn't... feeling my best, exactly.
Got it?
（えりな）いいわね
（緋沙子）あっ はい
Y-Yes.
Erina-sama is impressive!
さすが えりな様　何事にも
常に勝者であろうとするご意志
She's determined to be the victor
in anything and everything.
感服です
How worthy of admiration!
（えりな）いやぁ～ん
Yukihira Souma...
幸平創真
私の料理で 君を否定してあげます
I will teach you your place with my cooking.
I will show you what an egg dish worthy of Tohtsuki is made of.
しかと ご覧に入れましょう
遠月にふさわしい
卵料理の王道というものをね
Is a buffet like one of those all-you-can-eat places?
（創真）
あ～ ビュッフェってのは確か
バイキングみたいなやつだっけ
I have no idea what breakfast
at a luxury hotel looks like.
高級ホテルの朝食なんて
ピンと来ねえけど…
Guess I'll give this a shot.
とりあえず作ってみっか
If you're talking egg dishes...
卵料理と言えば…
In Japanese cuisine, it'd be dashimaki eggs.
和食なら だし巻き卵
With Western cuisine,
scrambled eggs sounds about right!
洋食なら
スクランブルエッグあたりだな
あむっ
Yum!
（創真）うめえ～っ！
（生徒たち）ええっ
Self-Praise
It's delicious.
うまい　うまいけども
これじゃ だめなんだよなぁ
No doubt about that,
but it's not enough.
Something new for the menu, huh?
（城一郎）新メニューか
面白(おもしれ)えもん作ったなぁ
That was quite interesting...
but I'm vetoing it.
でも却下だ
Huh?!
（創真）えっ なんでだよ 親父
うまいって言ってたじゃん
Why, Dad?!
You thought it was good!
Listen up, Souma.
いいか 創真　うちは定食屋だぜ
We're a diner.
Our customers come to Yukihira
because they're looking for diner food.
（城一郎）
客は定食屋らしい品を求めて
ゆきひらに来るんだ
Making off-the-wall dishes simply because you can won't win anyone over.
そこから外れた突飛な品を作っても
しょうがねえってこった
Trying to dazzle them with something novel isn't going to work.
（創真）
奇をてらっただけの料理じゃだめだ
I need to make something that's both classic and classy enough to be served here. But also...
高級ホテルにふさわしい
卵料理の定番メニュー
An innovative dish that will make a vibrant contribution to the breakfast table.
新鮮な 驚きのある一品を
提案してもらいたい
There's got to be some kind of twist to
the dish, something fresh and unexpected.
（創真）そこに何か１つ
驚きを加えるアイデアを
I've got it!
（創真）そうだ
（タクミ）完成だ！
I'm done!
This breakfast is a culmination
of the Aldinis' expertise!
これぞ アルディーニの技術を
尽くした朝食
ウォーッ！　待っていろ 幸平
Just you wait, Yukihira!
Wait till you see my ultimate dish!
（タクミ）
この俺の 至高の料理を！
Just go to sleep if you're done, Bro.
できたんなら早く寝なよ　兄ちゃん
What should I do?
どうしよう　どうしよう
早くメニューを決めないと
What should I do?!
I have to decide on a menu!
Just make your own food, Tadokoro.
田所らしい料理を作りゃいいんだ
それでいいんだ
That's enough.
Your cooking reflects your hospitality.
心遣い(ホスピタリティ)　それが
君の料理にはある
Hm...
Not everyone can stand to eat
a lot of food during breakfast,
朝は たくさん食べられない人も
いるから―
so maybe I should go with something on the lighter side.
ボリュームがありすぎない
メニューのほうがいいかな
Something lighter...
ボリューム…
そっか　それなら！
Right! I get it now!
Hey, you!
What?!
タァーッ！
Okay, I think I have a clear idea
of what I want to do now.
よし　イメージ固まったぜ
さっそく試作を…
Better start testing right away—
Whoa!
あ ビビった！　誰だ お前？
Who are you?
Hm...
ふーん
なかなかおいしい品ができそうね
Looks like you'll make a pretty good dish.
Huh?
あ… ああ そう？　サンキュー
Oh, yeah.
Thanks.
Who is she?
（創真）何だ こいつ
Her skin and hair are snow white.
肌… 髪… 白っ
ウフッ
（アリス）明日の朝が楽しみね
Tomorrow morning will be quite the show.
Good evening—
では ごきげんよ…
うぐっ！
Ow!
（アリス）イッターイ！
（創真）あ…
Come on!
ちょっと もう！
突っ立ってないで どいてよね
Don't just stand there! Get out of the way!
But you told me to stand here, Miss.
（黒木場(くろきば)リョウ）けど お嬢が
この位置で立ってろって言ったから
I also told you to only do that when I'm trying to intimidate someone!
（アリス）それは相手を
威嚇(いかく)する時だけとも言ったはずだわ
私の斜め後ろで斜に構えてると
すごみが良い感じなの！
When you stand off to the side looking like you're ready to pounce,
my intimidation factor goes way, way up!
Hey!
あっ あれはどうしたの？
あの ごりごりボール
Where'd they go?
Where are your balls?
I forgot them somewhere.
どっかに忘れた
I can't believe this!
信じられない！
They add a lot to the intimidation factor too!
あれもすごみを出すのに
良い塩梅(あんばい)なんだから！
You're so absentminded!
ほんっと でくの棒ね！
Oh, I'm sorry.
ああっ ごめんあそばせ
何のお話だったかしら
What were we talking about?
Oh, we weren't really talking at all.
あ… いや
話って話は全然してなかったけど
お前ら
もう作る品 決まったわけ？
So you know what you're making already?
Pretty much.
まあね
Good luck on your recipe testing.
あなたも支度 頑張ってね～
Later.
それじゃ
What was that about?
何だったんだ？
That was Yukihira Souma-kun.
（アリス）
あれが幸平創真君だってさ
うわさのわりには
なんだか期待外れみたいね
Despite all the rumors,
he doesn't seem to be anything special.
あんな料理を作るつもりなんて
フフッ
I can't believe he's planning to make that.
よほど不合格になりたいのかしら
He must really want to fail this test.
The Following Morning
Test
Whoa!
うおっ 広(ひれ)え～っ！
Hall A
This place is huge!
Hey, wake up!
（男子生徒Ｉ）おい 寝るな
Sorry.
（男子生徒Ｊ）ああ すまん
Oh, Tadokoro's here.
あっ 田所もこの会場か
Man
She's writing the "man" character again.
“人”の字をのんでいる
（創真）おっ タクミもいるじゃん
（タクミ）おっ…
Takumi's here too?
Yukihira!
幸平！
Looks like he's saying something,
but I can't make it out from this distance.
（創真）
何か言ってるけど 遠くて分からん
I'll win this time for sure!
Okay, so this is my spot.
えっと 俺の場所はここだな
Oh.
Hm?
Nakiri! Guess we're right next to each other.
薙切 お隣じゃん
Y-Yukihira-kun?!
ゆゆ… 幸平君？
We sure run into each other a lot!
合宿入ってから よく会うな
（えりな）
どれだけ神出鬼没なの？　この男
Why does he keep popping up everywhere?!
心臓に悪い
It's bad for my heart.
This will be the first time I get to see you cook.
何気に
お前の料理見んの 初めてだな
Well, it's a golden opportunity to show him how superior I am to him.
（えりな）まあ 私の力を
見せつけるには好都合ね
Yes, feel free to savor the gap
between my cooking and yours.
ええ 存分に味わうといいわ
私と君の料理の差を
Huh?
あ？　食べ比べするってこと？
You want to compare our dishes?
Sure, but after the test's over, okay?
別にいいけど課題の後でな
あっ ち… 違う！
そういうことじゃなくて
N-No!
That's not what I meant!
My sarcasm went right over his head!
皮肉が通じない…
まっ お互い頑張ろうや
Well, let's do our best.
It looks like you're planning to
make some kind of soufflé.
君 もしかして
スフレの何かを作るつもり？
Yup!
うん　俺はオムレツでいくわ
It's going to be a kind of omelette.
I'll whip the egg whites into a
meringue before cooking the dish,
卵白をメレンゲ状に泡立ててから
焼くことで―
普通のオムレツじゃ味わえない
食感に仕上がる
so the omelette will have a unique texture.
That's the soufflé omelette.
それがスフレオムレツだ
予想外の食感に出会うことも
料理の驚きの１つだよな
An novel texture is one of the surprises a dish can spring, y'know?
What?
何だよ
No, nothing.
いいえ　何でも…
（えりな）食感… ね
Texture, huh.
Each of you is ready to present your dish, I assume?
（堂島）
各自 料理を出す準備はできたな？
I will now explain the conditions for passing the test.
これより合格条件の説明に入る
First, let me introduce the judges.
まずは審査員の紹介だ
（子供たち）わーい！
（男子生徒Ｋ）こ… 子供？
K-Kids?!
These are the people who grow and produce ingredients for Tohtsuki Resort Hotels.
（堂島）
遠月リゾートが提携している
食材の生産者の方々
Their families are present as well.
そして そのご家族だ
Every year, they serve as judges at this camp.
毎年 この合宿で
審査を務めてくださっており―
I've informed them that the theme is an inspired egg dish.
“驚きのある卵料理”という
テーマも お伝えしてある
S-So many.
（男子生徒Ｌ）す… すげえ人数
Their judging is quite accurate.
審査は非常に正確でおいでだ
（鶏卵(けいらん)の徳蔵(とくぞう)）ウッハッハッハッハ
おかげさまでなぁ
A hearty thanks to all!
You may assume that I won't even touch anything poorly made.
Tokuzou of the Chicken Egg
不出来な品には
食いつかんと思っておくれ
Kousuke of the String Bean
（さやいんげんの耕助(こうすけ)）フッフフ
Kyuusaku of the Natural Cheese
（ナチュラルチーズの久作(きゅうさく)）
ヌゥ～ッ
These guys know their shit!
このおっさんたち…
Know Their Shit
They're way too intimidating!
（女子生徒Ｅ）貫禄ありすぎ…
So scary!
（男子生徒Ｍ）めちゃくちゃ 怖(こえ)ぇ
Tohtsuki Resort's kitchen and service staff will also join the judging team.
（堂島）
そして 我が遠月リゾートから―
調理部門とサービス部門の
スタッフたちも審査に加わる
The steward of the service department!
（男子生徒Ｎ）
サービス部門を率いる給仕長
Sakuma Tokihiko
Steward, Tohtsuki Resort
Even Chef Doujima's right-hand chef is here!
（男子生徒Ｏ）
堂島シェフの右腕の料理人まで
Sena Hiromi
Sous Chef, Tohtsuki Resort
There are two judging criteria.
合格基準は２つ
One is whether your dish displays inspiration worthy of acknowledgment by professional producers and staff.
生産者のプロと 現場のプロ
彼らに認められる発想があるか否か
そして もう１つは―
The other is to have 200 servings of your dish consumed in the next two hours.
今から２時間以内に
200食以上 食してもらうこと
200食かぁ
200 servings, huh?
I see.
（タクミ）
なるほど　老若男女さまざまな客層
There is a wide range of diners:
men and women, young and old.
They intend to simulate an actual hotel breakfast.
まさにホテルの朝食を
再現してるわけか
This challenge closely mirrors a real-life situation.
これは極めて
現場の実践に近い課題だ
以上を満たした者を合格とする
Those who fulfill those two criteria will pass the test!
Very well, honored judges, please enjoy the breakfast in all of the exam halls.
では 各会場 審査員の皆様―
朝食のひとときを
存分に お楽しみください
May the judging begin!
審査開始！
Here it is!
（男子生徒Ｐ）お待たせしました
（女子生徒Ｇ）いらっしゃいませ
Welcome!
Here you go!
（男子生徒Ｑ）どうぞ
Please enjoy!
（女子生徒Ｈ）
お召し上がりください
Oh, how fragrant.
（従業員Ａ）
あら 香ばしい香り　これは？
What is this?
It's a frittata.
（タクミ）フリッタータです
I see, an Italian egg dish.
（従業員Ａ）
イタリア発祥の卵料理ね
It's made with cheese.
チーズをからめて焼き上げてある
As far as breakfast goes,
it might be a bit boring.
（従業員Ｂ）でも
朝食としては 少し平凡な気も…
Not at all.
I'll be serving my frittata to you as a salad.
僕のフリッタータは サラダとして
召し上がっていただきます
I'll break the frittata into pieces,
フリッタータを
ざっくり粗くほぐして―
and toss them with vegetables!
野菜とあえる
Then I sprinkle some balsamic vinaigrette and Parmesan cheese on top.
（タクミ）バルサミコソースと
パルミジャーノチーズを散らして…
And it's done.
完成
I present to you the insalata frittata.
インサラータ･フリッタータ
"Insalata"?
インサラータ？
That's Italian for "salad", right?
サラダって意味よね
あむっ
Wow! It's delicious!
あっ おいしい～
The texture of the fluffy eggs
and the crisp raw vegetables!
フワッフワの卵と
シャキシャキした生野菜の食感
And the light balsamic vinaigrette
ties it all together!
それに さっぱりとしたソースが
口の中で混じり合って…
Amazing!
（従業員Ｂ･Ａ）すご～い
こんなサラダ 食べたことな～い
I've never eaten a salad like this!
Grazie!
グラッツェ！
U-Um...
（恵）あっ あの…
（３人）ジ～ッ！
P-Please have some if you'd like.
よっ… よかったら
召し上がってください
ひとくちサイズの朝食おでんです
It's single-bite breakfast oden!
What? Oden for breakfast?
なんと！ おでん
Hm...
うむ　しかも串の先にあるのは―
And on top of that, this is
a quail egg on the skewer!
うずらの卵だ
Hm, I see.
うむ　なるほど
Chicken eggs aren't the only eggs available.
鶏卵だけが卵ではない
こう来た… か
That's her angle.
ふぁ～　ほっとする味…
What a comforting taste!
The mild broth fills your mouth with every bite.
かむたびにまろやかなダシが
ジワジワと染み出てくる
The vegetables were cut
to match the quail egg's size.
うずらの卵にサイズをそろえた
野菜もカラフルで―
They're so colorful that you
can't resist picking them up!
つい手に取ってしまう楽しさだ
（久作）ジ～ッ！
（恵）ひいっ！
Will you...
（久作）わしの―
marry my grandson?
孫に嫁いでくれんか
What?!
Uh, um...
いや あの… ええっ？
What?!
（男子生徒Ｒ）
いらっしゃいませ！
Hall E
（瀬名(せな)博巳(ひろみ)）
おお　面白いなぁ
This is cool.
A loco moco donburi at a buffet, huh.
ビュッフェでロコモコ丼か
Hm...
（瀬名）うん　あむっ
んっ！　ロコモコ丼には―
Loco moco is typically topped with gravy,
グレイビーソースをかけるのが
定番だが―
but here you've used a vinaigrette sauce!
これはソースビネグレット！
The light acidity of the white wine vinegar
白ワインビネガーの
さわやかな酸味が―
heightens the creamy texture of the yolk and the juiciness of the meat!
卵黄のとろみと肉のジューシーさを
引き立ててる
力がみなぎるような一品！
This is a very fortifying dish.
Well done!
すばらしい完成度だ！
Yeah!
（郁魅）オッケ！
I was able to leverage the recipe
I came up with in the Don RS.
丼研で試作した品が生かせた
And it'll be a piece of cake
to make 200 servings of this.
200食達成は楽勝だな
Have we met before?
（アリス）あなた…
（郁魅）ああっ
どっかで見覚えが…
あっ てめえ…
Huh?!
You?!
Oh!
ああ えりなの下についてた子ね
You were one of Erina's lackeys.
Funny, I haven't seen you around recently.
あれぇ？
でも最近 見かけなかったよねぇ
Oh, I get it.
あっ そっかぁ
Did Erina decide you weren't worthy of her?
えりなに見限られちゃったの？
Shut up!
うるせえ
ぶっ飛ばすぞ こらぁっ！
I'm gonna beat the crap out of you!
My apologies!
（アリス）あら ごめんあそばせ
（郁魅）ううっ… ううっ…
Hm?
何だ？　あいつの料理
What's with her dish?
A boiled egg, another unshelled egg,
ゆで卵に
殻がついたままの卵に―
and a raw egg on a small plate?
割った生卵？
That's supposed to be a dish?
あれで料理のつもりかよ
None of the guests are going near her booth.
客も全然 寄りついてねえし
何考えてんだ？
What's she thinking?
Hall A
Here you go.
どうぞ
It's Eggs Benedict.
エッグ･ベネディクトでございます
（従業員Ｃ）
おおっ なんという美しさ
What beauty!
They're like brilliant jewels!
（従業員Ｄ）
まばゆく輝く宝石のよう
Eggs Benedict...
（佐久間(さくま)時彦(ときひこ)）
エッグ･ベネディクト
The dish consists of an English muffin
topped with poached eggs and bacon,
マフィンの上に ポーチドエッグや
ベーコンなどを乗せ―
then finished with a slightly
acidic hollandaise sauce.
酸味のあるオランデーズソースを
かけた品
It's a mainstay on American breakfast menus
アメリカでは
朝食の王道メニューの１つだが―
and certainly nothing one would consider new.
決して新しい料理とは言えない
What's innovative about this item?
この品のどこに驚きがあると？
The poached egg melts on your tongue
and is perfection itself.
舌がとろけそうな
ポーチドエッグの完璧な半熟
The hollandaise sauce has such a refined acidity.
オランデーズソースの上品な酸味
The bacon is crisp,
カリカリに焼いたベーコンと
ほのかに甘いマフィン
and the muffin has a subtle sweetness.
The perfect harmony of all these
flavors envelops the tongue.
それらが混然一体となった味が
舌を包む
いや それだけではない
No, that's not the only thing.
What is this brilliant golden powder?!
黄金に輝く この粉は？
からすみ
Dried mullet roe?!
She sprinkled dried mullet roe powder on the muffins?
からすみパウダーを
マフィンにまぶしてあるのか
I see. Fish roe is also a type of egg!
なるほど　魚卵もまた卵
The refined saltiness of the roe
meshed with the chicken egg yolk
からすみの高級感のある塩味が
鶏卵の黄身とからんで―
to produce this deep flavor!
この深い味わいを！
A particular restaurant in New York
that serves Eggs Benedict
“朝食の女王”
ニューヨークで
エッグ･ベネディクトを出す―
has been praised as the "queen of breakfast."
老舗の名店を称えた言葉だ
And this dish is truly worthy of a queen.
この品もまさしく 上級の一品
The taste is enough to make you kneel!
思わず かしずくうまさ！
But of course.
当然ですわ
（客たち）うわぁ～
（女性客Ａ）すてき！
Wonderful.
I'm melting.
（女性客Ｂ）とろけるわ～
（男子生徒Ｓ）えりな様～
Erina-sama...
Eggs Benedict-sama!
（一同）エッグ･ベネディクト様！
I should just give up
akiramechatte ii no ni
I feel I should quit
yamechae tte omou no ni
But I can't get myself to start running away
nigedasu koto sae dekinakute
I keep wavering in my uncertainty
furafura furafura
Because I lack confidence
jishin ga nakute sono sei de
I can't manage to bring out the true me
jibun jishin mo dasenakute
And in this vicious spiral, I keep losing my confidence
jishin nakushte supairaru
Going round and round, round and round
guruguru guruguru
But now that we've met each other
demo deaeta kara
I won't lose sight of you
mou miushinawanai yo
As long as your smile is there, I need nothing else
egao ga areba iranai nanimo
I don't need extravagant materials or gaudy decorations
gouka na shina mo hade na kazari mo iranai kara
Let's get around the table and garnish our meal
shokutaku kakomou kinou no misu mo
with yesterday's failures and tomorrow's worries
fuan na asu mo soete
Really, I don't need anything
nee iranai nanimo
I don't need exquisite seasonings or stylish food arrangements
kotta ajitsuke mo shareta moritsuke mo iranai kara
Even if the taste of the tears is salty
namida no aji wa mou shoppai to shite mo
But if in the end I can still smile
saigo ni itsumo waraetara
That's my spice
sore ga supaisu
Nakiri Erina
200 Servings
Nakiri Erina!
（堂島）薙切えりな　200食達成！
200 servings, complete!
は… 早い　だが俺もすぐ追いつく
She's fast!
But I'm right behind her!
What about Yukihira?!
幸平はどうだ
I'm halfway there!
（恵）あと半分　創真君は？
What about Souma-kun?!
What's wrong?!
（タクミ）どうした？　幸平
Yukihira?
No way!
（恵）そんな！
He's still at fewer than ten servings!
まだ10皿以下？
End
Next Episode
（悠姫･涼子）
次回「食戟のソーマ」
Next time on Shokugeki no Souma,
the fourteenth dish.
（涼子）14品目
It's hell!
（悠姫）地獄やでえ～
Menu
Metamorphosis
Metamorphosis.
（悠姫･涼子）
「メタモルフォーゼ」
I'm going to ferment.
（涼子）発酵しちゃう
（悠姫）イヤッフー！
I won't let anyone take
my No. 1 spot at Polar Star!